[Music]
this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se-
radio.net SC radio is brought to you by
the it computer society and by It
software Magazine online at computer.org
software hi everyone I'm Priyanka Ragin
for software engineering radio and today
I'm chatting with Shahar binyamin the
CEO and co-founder of Inigo to talk
about graphql security Shahar is a
software engineer by trade he has
extensive experience working on many
high-profile Enterprise applications and
security projects He has written several
articles and given talks at technology
conferences all of which have added to
our show notes so welcome to the show
Shahar hey Panka great to be here one of
the things we've done is we've done a
deep dive on graphql which is episode
530 so listeners can obviously listen to
that episode to understand the history
in the basics of graphql having said
that since we have you on the show and
it's been a while since we did that I
have to ask you if you can just briefly
Define for us what is graphql I know
it's tough but maybe a little bit one or
two lines and then can you also tell us
why the state of graph CLE adoption is
so great or whether you think it's
otherwise but I I personally think
there's a big adoption in the graph
space and what is the state of graphql
adoption yeah absolutely great question
so graphql is mer a spec it's an API
spec that came out of Facebook now meta
back in 2016 and it's a quy based API
and really was there to solve some of
the rest limitations of under fetching
and over fetching it's a great tool that
really expedite frontend developers
allowed them to move firly extract any
data that they want in any type of
hierarchy and we've seen a lot of it
when it comes out of Facebook um we've
seen the open source communities
specifically Developers really adopt in
it and you can actually find an
implementation of graphql in any
programming language uh you might think
of now when we think about adoption of
graphql I would say that like any
developer driven technology developer
brings it into the organization they get
all hyped about it and and like any new
technology like let's put this
everywhere it doesn't work everywhere
but it does work really well when when
it's the right place uh like client
server or we have an open API so it had
a a rough patch at the beginning with
rejections and like lot of excitement
lot of rejection and now it's really
finding its place and actually becoming
mainstream in many Enterprises and just
kind of following up on that question
you had an article on dev Zone which was
titled you love graphql now how to make
sure your organization does too so why
do you think graphql is popular among
developers and what could they do to
bring it into their organizations maybe
you have like a case study where you
have you worked with a company where the
developers liked it and then they had a
success story of bringing the
organization in usually there's always
one champion and maybe this person
worked with graphql in their previous
company and that's the story we see a
lot and then people move around and they
say hey we know about this new
technology and there's always a new
feature there's always a new product uh
some Legacy companies say okay it's time
to refresh our stack and then grq is
becoming a discussion can we do this and
front end developers when they hear
about this say yes this is what we want
so now you have the backend champion and
the front end team pushing for the same
thing and usually it will start with the
side product uh with some exploration
but now if you want you as the champion
to push this down the org then you need
more supporters and when it even gets to
a point that you would like to
productize it what we're seeing in a lot
of technology companies this new concept
of platform teams or API teams some
called them architect teams or core team
the names really is vast and now you
basically need to ask them to own this
other type of API as part of the API
responsibility and you need to have a
good reason a good mandate and a really
good set of building blocks to allow an
organization to adopt new technology if
we think about the equivalent to
kubernetes when developers brought it in
and then they said to the devops hey now
you need to operate this and maybe two
minutes later the security team will
come and say Hey Now how do we secure it
we can see a similar story with graphql
with the platform teams those API teams
they say hey what is this you're asking
us to do this but how do we do this and
I'm sure we'll break it down that's very
interesting to summarize I think what
you're saying this is probably true for
any new technology right they go through
a review board and then pass it on to a
central team which then allows the whole
sort of a spread of that new technology
across the organization and then the
security teams come
I think that probably then goes on to my
next question on why is graphql security
important it's a let's unfold this
question okay okay when adopting a a
free form API which is the nature of
graphql which is super powerful
intentionally or unintentionally in many
cases it couldn't get abused so graphql
because of its nature it opens the door
to a new paradigm of attack surfaces
think think about all the attack you can
have with stressed API and now add whole
new set level of tools that are
specifically for graphql you can see
this I guess in four places of attack
surfaces you can think about the spec
itself can be abused which is
interesting the parser the logic and we
know that not all graphql
implementations are the same you can
think about resource exhaustion when
you're allowed to ask questions in
hierarchy what is the cost of such a
call are you protecting from data
leakage which is much more open if you
think about rest again if we take a step
back it's a contract between the sender
and the reper these are the question
these are the response very strict
graphql is
free not all requests are the same
they're unlimited number of requests
unless you put the Right Guard girls so
same as the responses and lastly how do
you bring these all Notions of Access
Control that you already have in your
system and bring them to graphql as well
so a whole new set of challenges when
who's the owner of them that's another
question okay wow that's that's great
because it's uh very interesting cuz I
also noticed in the oos top 10 2023 API
Edition I I noticed that there were so
many examples on every category which
had like how can it be abused by graphql
apis you know so um that's very
interesting from what you said because I
think that's one of the things I thought
we can dive in a bit deep in the next
section but what are your thoughts on
that well absolutely like anything you
can do with rest you can do with graphql
and more what sometimes is frustrating
that you go to the OSAP website or other
API gateways or other WFT tools and you
go and see what they can do for you for
security and sometimes it's very limited
and sometimes it ends with just a list
of
recommendations so how do we take these
recommendations and put them in place
that is a big question and it's great in
the last I think two years specifically
there is a lot of content about Gruff
kill security and articles like this are
perfect because before that the
information out there was like extremely
limited people are talking about height
and depth and N1 which is a great
example but it's tip of the of the
iceberg and if you really want to
increase education uh around it more and
more articles and information and blog
posts are coming out there really
enriching the community and which is
very important just because of the the
variation of implementations of graph
out there interesting so I I think as
the implementations differ you're saying
that the documentation also has to keep
up to know the different ways it can be
exploited when last year what something
that we've done is we wanted to be super
critical about are these vulner
abilities really exist so we have done
two interesting things first of all we
looked into the cve database and we just
wrote graphql to see what what will come
up and and then we saw a lot of
incidents and remember to import not all
incidents are reported not all the ones
who are reported are actually getting
the cve but you start to see a thre and
then we try to
analyze where those vulnerabilities
really rely and you can see a lot about
authorization a lot about Doss and then
you have the other classical like cod
execution and injections and maybe
disclosure so we had so much fun doing
this exercise we did the same with
hacker one and we went to the hacker one
vulnerability uh database and we said
let's try to do the same and it actually
the first one dated to 2018 which is
even before the first cve and we've
noticed bounce is really ranging from
250 even to 20K and that's the beginning
that's all the different implementations
are coming out and companies are going
out say hey can someone we don't even
have the tools to try to hack ourself
and we need help here this is New
Territory this is new water and for
hacker one all of it was almost 90% was
about authorizations flow which makes
sense you don't usually go to hacker one
for someone to Dos you so all those
attacks are out there and we can talk
about it's interesting to see what
hackers how they do it and we can break
it down okay so I think one of the
things I should ask you before we move
to the next section is also why and how
do attackers hunt the graph qia is it
just because the fact that like you said
in the beginning the rest contract is
very rigid so therefore it's is this
more
easier okay so what what do hackers do
with graph I yeah
exactly and how they do it and they well
they do two things first they detect it
then they will fingerprint it and then
they will abuse it so let's talk about
detecting Graff it will always return
something which is one of the biggest
blind spot of every graphql owner or
developer that there's a big blind spot
on the responses and errors they because
the error or the content or the intent
relies in the body and not in the HTTP
respon so there's always response even
if it's hey you're wrong there is a
response and there are very uh specific
Notions on how companies put their
graphical endpoint it could be SLG
graphql Cory API playground SLG
graphical there are specific Notions
that are very very very common to use so
nothing is preventing an abuser to go to
any domain and just write SLG graphql
and send a query it doesn't need to be a
valid query it's just send in something
so you can go over every company any
domain and start say hey something will
reply at some point and you can automate
this obviously and once you get the Json
reply if does doesn't matter what is the
reply then you know then you have a
graphql server or an endpoint out there
so that's the detect part now based on
their reply and again you don't need you
don't need to know the introspection you
don't need to know the schema you can
just send type name and again please
don't use this it's very basic once you
hear it now but then why not use it and
so don't we don't want to encourage
abusiveness but we want to educate that
the ones who actually own graph servers
their response could be very different
between the different implementations
one of them can have the warding syn
syntax error and one of them can have
the wording syntax graphql error so
based on this you can actually
fingerprint what
implementation is being used and in some
cases you can even fingerprint the
version it could be PHP goang JavaScript
Java hasle rust they're all built by
different open source communities and
they all have different levels of
efforts in them or dedication in them
and there's a lot of you also published
ones there's other who published a whole
table
that identify the vulnerabilities in
each implementation in go there's a few
implementations of of graph kill server
so knowing able to detect able to
fingerprint the implementation and be
able
to now equip all those you can run
against the vulnerabilities of that
specific implementation and that's just
a spec abuse it goes even before so
that's what out there so what can you do
I don't know don't use a
classic endpoint so people can guess and
and we can talk about what what does
mean really to harden a graph endpoint I
think that's very interesting because
it's opened up a whole lot of questions
which I hadn't really thought about
about the hardening part yeah I think
that's interesting so I think the first
thing you said is also that's the big
takeaway from this is also not to make
your you know the end points have to be
a bit not so easy to find right I think
the very first thing you should tell
people to protect their graph q and and
I'm not um I'm not the biggest supporter
of security bisc but anything you can do
to reduce automation against you it's
just good practice absolutely because
nowadays I think automation is yeah
everybody's running those scripts to do
everything so I think it obviously makes
sense to follow security by OB you know
OB even though it's not really obscurity
actually security by obscurity even
though it's not the most intelligent
thing to do yeah I I think now it would
be a good time to like dive into some of
those issues that you talked about like
uh briefly alluded to the fact that one
of the things that you see in a lot of
your research has shown that the
authorization errors they seem to crop
up a lot in these use cases so one of
the things I noticed when I was reading
the oos top 10 API security checklist
was the broken object level
authorization where essenti one of the
things you do you have these API
endpoints where they might be quering
something by an ID for example and that
seems to be one of a very good attack
vectors and there was an example there
also with this can be abused by for
graphql API so is that something that
you can just uh briefly talk us through
what you have seen I'll break it into my
answer into three first of all
visibility and then attribute access
control and then role based access
control the first thing which is the
base line is even knowing it's happening
or ability to know it happened it really
goes into deep observability and
monitoring tool that is also still a big
gap when it comes to graphql is the
ability to know when these things happen
in case of an audit or an incident or
even trying to figure out what goes
wrong and what can be improved and we're
seing many many companies that it's a
massive blind spot everything all the
graphical traffic and all sort of
attempts to to put in their rest hat and
say hey I'll just throw everything to
my log tool to my SIM splan or do dog
doesn't really help and really really
hard to create insights and
understanding of what's happening so if
you're blind to everything there's no
point in trying to but that's the first
step first line of the fence is even
knowing what's going on and then later
medify and the second thing let's talk
about role based Access Control your
schema could be big or could be small
but doesn't mean that everyone should
see it and the idea is is to bring your
existing Notions of roles in your
organizations maybe Anonymous user maybe
a member a user an admin and really
shape the intros the schema when call
for introspection to not to only allow
what this specific role is allowed to do
and enforce it at that time so when they
call introspect or when they call cories
or
mutations you start to differentiate who
can access what in the schema and the
sooner you do it the better before it
hit your business
logic and lastly is the aback is like
where do you put those business logic
that are specific to your org of who can
access what specific data fields in your
org if you're thinking about I'm trying
to get a specific let's let's take a
Twitter or ex's and example maybe
Anonymous user should not be allowed to
read comments so if they never logged in
if they don't have a jot if they try to
have secur imitation about comment
information they're blocked immediately
they cannot but if they are logged in a
user and they try to get the filled
comments then you have to write your own
unique business logic that says hey this
user is user seven they cannot access
and that is more hard work but both of
them are needed because you don't want
to trigger this business logic if that
user should not even be allowed to ask
for that field so you have to have a
some combination of both hope it makes
sense so you're saying essentially what
I understand is also like have like
various levels of check so like the
first level Cuts you off here and then
you go one level deeper then you have
another check like the aback kind of
check which you said okay mistakes
mistakes always happen mistakes always
happen changes of fields always happen
you can't think of the schema as a
static thing developers around the or
will constantly will continue to change
the schema add Fields reduce fields at
the end of the day those vulnerabilities
or hacks or data leakage or data
manipulation happens because of a stake
and so even so the more guardrails you
can put even as part of the development
life cycle in your cicd are crucial and
the more checkpoints that you have the
more protection you will have down the
road because changes of the schema
happens all the time more than you can
even imagine especially in large
organizations okay so the thing is that
um when you have a lot of checks can you
tell me a little bit of do we have to
have some guard for the performance also
or uh is that just a tradeoff is it oh
absolutely it's super
important because it cause it could
cause resource exhaustion or dos and
Depends an attack that we see see it's a
Dos attack basically if you get to learn
if you're an abuser or actually it
happens unintentionally not as abusive
intentionally abusive coal it just
happens there's a change in the back end
and some field used to cost one
millisecond but now it costs 10
millisecond uh because it computes on
the fly or whatever it is and then a big
quy or is calling for this and suddenly
there's a change and that calls becom
super long and maybe the parcel will
fill maybe the graph server is in maybe
the the timeout will happen and you can
cause a Dos or you're just consuming so
much resources that is very expensive to
your order that goes back to that that
blind spot that lack of what we start
calling field level analytics and
subgraph visibility is the ability to
really to
trace in this graphql journey
what is slow what is slowing you down
and be able to have those platform teams
really have um be able to have a
database conversation with those
subgraph
owners we see this all the time so I
think it uh so from what I'm saying the
observability piece is very important so
how you set your What fields you query
to provide the insights right to your
performance yes what Fields your users
are using or customers are using to quy
things because if something cost cost a
lot of time and and it will be asked
again and again and again 10,000 times
in one query and that query has been
sent a thousand times in a
second it's not hard to predict what's
going to happen yeah in fact I think
this was the one that also was mentioned
a lot in some of the Articles and blogs
I read they talked about graphql being
very susceptible to these B B attacks
and then and people are just like trying
to Brute Force these batch attacks and
then and then try to bypass the rate
limiting so that's something could you
maybe give us an example like have if
it's okay to talk about something where
you've seen an example I mean you don't
have to mention companies but maybe just
an example these type of attacks it's
hard to admit but this is where your
existing API Gateway is failing you it's
notion to I'm going to give two examples
of rate limited for graphql uh can hurt
you the existing tools of counting API
calls they don't they don't work for
graphql it doesn't matter for graphql
when you think about rate limiting uh
you have to stop counting how many calls
that happen versus you need to start
counting operations and mutations and I
will break it into two things to have in
mind when it comes through grq as the
first think about field level rate
limiting which is the classic example of
Brute Force one API that will fly
through all of your existing security
tools can have thousand or 10,000 login
attempts with different passwords so you
have a very easy Brute Force attempt
that goes undetected without the proper
monitoring and and rate living in place
and you can do this the same with the
example we talked about before if we
know that there is a very expensive
field an abuser can just Hammer this
field in one call or again and again
again repeatedly with multiple quaries
or multiple aliases and just Hammer this
field so that is thinking about field
level rate limiting and why it's
important to di of and understand the
intent of their request and put some I
guess tighten the knobs on those
guardrails if it's Max aliases or Max
Root operations there's many ways to to
address this problem or rate limit how
many times a login can happen and if you
tie it back to what we spoke about
before with the roles maybe Anonymous
users can only do five of them in minute
and maybe an admin could do a 100 of
them so how all of them just starting to
work together and the other side of rate
limiting when it comes to graphql is
start thinking about cost based rate
limiting and that means you have to
start processing the response again very
unique to graphql are you counting how
many objects have been returned and why
is this important it's important because
you want to protect from resource
exhaustion you also want to protect from
data scraping uh and we see this all the
time when you have maybe a Marketplace
and you have a competitor trying to
figure out the pricing that you have
they're just like hammering your
listing so by monitoring those heavy
objects you count how many objects have
been returned per user per role and if
you want to take this to the extreme you
can also have a dynamically assigned
weights meaning if you realize that
specific queries started to be more
expensive because a field again Fields
change all the time databases change all
the time and if you can have something
fully managed uh that you can detect oh
this Fields suddenly more important you
give more weights to that more credits
you can arguably say and then you can
constantly monitoring and keep a your
health state of your uh operability of
graphql in a good shape wow that's
that's really good that's very
insightful I think one of the things uh
to just take away from that is there's
also this another attack vctor called
broken object property level
authorization so just just one of the
examples that what I wanted to ask I
thought it would be good to ask with an
example and then take you through it
because I think this this is one where
you know you have an suppose you have an
example of an online Marketplace that
offers like U you have two types of
users like a host who's used to rent out
their apartment and another type of
guest who actually wants to stay there
then some of the things that uh there's
usually like a call which says like
approve booking to the person who's
renting out their apartment and then the
payload will be like something
legitimate like approved is true comment
is check in after 3 p.m. and suddenly
this is one thing which I saw in some of
the blogs where said that they add
another entire New Field to the Json
structure like a malicious payload
saying they modify the price what was
there supposed to be an approval API now
just has like an extra field and then
that's suddenly bang money is gone from
this person right so like these kind of
things can you talk a little bit about
also this kind of property level
authorization that we need to have yeah
it's it's a great example and again I
would assume it happened because of
efficiency trying to trying to move fast
trying to empower maybe there's an admin
function that they use and suddenly it
was exposed suddenly the tree is exposed
even if introspection is closed there's
many ways like fine and others to know
what really app option is options are
with the mutations or with the
Quarry the way we think about this at an
iGo it really ties goes to the
enforcement of role-based access control
and rooll base access control is very
could be very very deep it could go all
the way to a filled level do I want to
expose an email do I want to expose a
name or a last name or an SSN based on
their role
it can also be an attributes in the
mutation arguments meaning that in this
example when someone is calling a
mutation and trying to enforce an
argument a variable that is not supposed
to be there first that variable will be
rejected and lastly you can also and
that's another common attack we didn't
talk about this which is exposed you can
also put injection in any free form
aspects of graphql from operation name
to Alas name to a varable information so
how do you run validation against any
input field uh it also critical to put
so we've been talking like for 30
minutes and we just exposed a lot of
different vulnerabilities of graphql and
the more the conversation deepen more
things surface and it's really
challenging to chase them because at the
moment you thought as the champion of
graph G that you're bringing new
technology into your org and suddenly
you're deep into conversations about hey
how do we operate this at scale how do
we secure it and you might not have that
expertise in your org and and we see
we've seen companies again the very very
large scale companies have dedicated
graphql developer teams which is very
very expensive you think about this but
the the reality is that the first movers
of graphql had to the first Enterprise
movers of graphql we can name coinbase
we can name credit Wayfair GitHub
happily or not happily they had to
invest a lot in those building blocks
and created a lot of innovation which is
phenomenal to see to kind of uh take it
back so this community-led effort for
doing a lot of this Innovation can you
tell us any of the kind of good tools
that came out of these uh Community Le
efforts to find out these graphql
issues there's a lot of post
blogs okay blog post blog post lot of
blogs a lot of tools there's a few open-
Source tools out there unfortunately
sometimes those tools are attached to
the specific implementations or the
programming L language they were written
at there are some commercial Solutions
out there there's some free Solutions
out there we're seen I think this is
just very very new in a year or two uh
we've seen a few open source attempts to
create a layer that does some sort of
gatekeeping around graph
quaries some of them do a good job some
of them are still early but that's great
it just means there's more education
about this and we're also seeing the
communities around them around gra
implementations starting to add a little
more rules about what is possible what
is
not which is I think the're phenomenal
for those who getting started uh because
off the shelf they can find something uh
that can help
them questionable if the these are
Enterprise grade Solutions so is there
any like recommended scanners that
developers can
use I I I will hesitate to answer in
this question I don't want to put
scanners examples out there for people
to be abused I would say that you can
think about a scanner that runs against
your graphql that fine vulnerabilities
that's a great option to include as part
of your cicd
my worry with those scanners is that
they need the counterpart they need the
ones that actually also run in your
production that can force real-time
protection and that is the key of of how
are we thinking about graph security a
real time ability to address to protect
to Monitor and alert and those scanners
they're great as part of your
development life cycle but how do you
get a slack alert when your most
critical mutation is failing again and
again and again and I think this is this
is the existing
pain that Gruff kill owners at scale are
are challenged
with how do they
know they don't unless they invest
heavily but the investment do you have
any examples where the investment was
worth the price is is that what is
stopping the teams from investing
because I think you gave us some great
examples but they look they seem to be
like you really need to inspect every
field and you know you need to go
through to find out a lot think behind
every field that you put and what are
the guard deals and sometimes that might
kind of slow you down right it does it
does slow you down it done create some
resistance and it does create uh
frustration and road map slowdowns as
engineer leaders are facing this
responsib ility of a new stack what we
all do is like hey what do we already
have that can work with Graff oh I have
this apigy or I have this Gateway it's
like what can they do for me with Gruff
G well very little and then they think
about performance monitor that we
touched before and we think about
observability and and said oh I just
going to put my splan or Dat Dog and
just send everything to everything to uh
all the logs to it it's super expensive
and again not everyone of your developer
teams have access to it and it doesn't
do a good job in providing that that
field level intake and then you start
say as your organization as your graph
evolve your organization will evolve
with it you start thinking about
composition and registry and your
platform teams will get super frustrated
with developers changing things and said
all it's time to enforce linting first
start to enforce rules so so how do you
get all of this as part of your API
management developer life cycle cicd how
do you get all of this component and
suddenly you have to deal with a lot of
things what's great to see is companies
coming up from the graph space like
anigo they're trying to think about like
an holistic solution that like hey let's
connect all the dots let's sit very
close to the graph kill server and let's
think about and this is It's A New
Concept let's think about graphql
management
what does that means what does that mean
to your or can we answer basic questions
about our graph apis and you'll be
surprised to know that like when you ask
like how many graphql API calls do you
have or how many unique graphql calls
people struggle to answer this question
it shouldn't be a hard question to
answer so when you think about
recommendation or com to this like
really ask your existing tool
or vendors you work with what can they
do for you when it comes to graphql what
we often see is down the not too long
after trying to enforce rest tools or
graphql we see that they that didn't
work and that caused a lot of
frustration and now you have to ask
yourself what do I do so the first years
of GRA kill adoption the mo the first
Enterprise movers of graphql went
homegrown let's build this
ourself but you can learn from this and
you can learn from what You' have done
and what can be productized what can be
generalized and can actually work for
your organization and you might not need
all of this you might only need some of
it but these are conversations to have
with your team I think one more thing I
wanted to ask you before I go into the
the graphql deployment piece was one of
the other attack vectors was the denial
of service which is also something we
didn't talk so much I mean I think we
kind of briefly talked about it in the
introduction is it is it true that
graphql is more susceptible to denial of
service
attacks it is very susceptible to
attacks more probably yes because it
exposed more uh there's more steps in
the way that could be
attacked the parser itself can be
attacked the business logic can be
attacked and then you have the database
connectivity that can cause data leakage
or Expos or data manipulation which in
some cases worse graphical responses
could leak information even if there's
errors some some implementation Returns
the stack or hence pii in the error
response you have to think if
introspection is a risk or not different
there's two different schools for that
one classic example that we like to give
about the spec attack things that don't
exist in rest directive attack what
happens if you overload a parser with
directives that don't exist and I mean
thousands of them I didn't sound as
trying to be abusive this could spin off
the parser it can overload the system
and you have a Dos attack even before
one line of your own code was was
executed so directive is attack is a
very common and and nice attack that we
like to share because it's very easy to
replicate but you have batching attacks
we mentioned alas attack that we
mentioned that can do do Doss fill
duplication can cause Doss uh directive
overloading nested quaries things people
don't talk about a lot is nested
fragments super easy to do and the list
goes on and those are just whole new set
of challenges that exist just for
graphql wow so then I think we have to
talk a little bit about the mitigation
strategies so one of the things I
learned when I reading a lot of these
blogs on the mitigation strategy was to
limit the depth of the queries what is
your take on that can you explain that
it's just the tip of the iceberg to
limit the uh you should you should limit
it unless you know someone is using it
so it ties goes back with like are
people using it do are frontend
developers actually using it if you
harden it too much you're you're herming
your own developers from using it so you
have to have a balance between knowing
how it's been used before limited so
throwing a few there depth height yeah
control no those those uh I call this
knobs like handles you want to control
how much people can play with this
aliases directive what characters are
allowed for injections and operation
name something we love to do is to force
operation aim because it kind of could
hint the intent of the sender and this
is not for intentionally abusive goals
but an abusive C happened by your own
team if you have the intent you know
who's doing this Max request size Max
request response or time how long it
took if you see a specific quy took 5
Seconds seconds maybe next time you
won't allow it so you have to also start
relying on historical data to make
decision moving forwards uh you want to
maybe block get request and only approve
post request a lot of handles you want
to make sure they're all locked and tied
and you might want to complete have a
set of rules between the roles because
you want to allow your admins or the
developers free
access but in production you want to
little more tight
really cool that's I think yeah these
are all very valid mitigation strategies
that I'm seeing so just being very
superficial and saying just limiting the
depth is not oh not not at all yeah but
if if two years ago you would Google
graph a text aex you only see three
things depth height n plus one there's
more much more I would see if we talking
about
mitigations the way you can think of
optionally think about this is some
abstraction
you have to think about the Corey coming
in let's call it Corey protection does
it look right height depth directives
does it go through the standard of Cory
is they're willing to accept the second
thing is it accessing the right Fields
so think about access control can it
access the right Fields based on the
role based on the identity of the
sender then you start thinking about
rate
limiting and say okay are we going to
allow this user who asks so many
questions or to get more information or
they're using something we're not going
to allow we allow only 10 login attempts
and they're sending 20 login attempts in
one call and then when processed look at
the response what's in there let's start
counting how many objects has been
returned so the next time they're
reaching out to us we say Hey you
already ask us too much or maybe it's
time to evaluate the internal Dynamic
cost of the how much actually cost us to
response to this
Cory and if you go to the extreme and
you're in a completely financially or
governed environment maybe you should
search for pii in the response either
specific fields or in the air response
this is a very expensive task to do in
real time so again you have to put like
a to be very mindful about what security
rules are you put now we were talking
about grff kill as in its open form this
does not align with everyone like if you
don't have to have a completely open
graphql introspection schema if you have
a strict client server situation yeah
those things should not be open and you
should really find a very good
implementation of operation registry
which is funny it's like you're
hardening your rest your graph C to look
like rest but it makes a lot of sense in
a client server environment that you're
only going to allow specific
pre-approved queries to come in but it
doesn't that doesn't make it's true to
everyone so having both of these options
to you are critical to be aware of okay
so it almost feels like maybe s it's not
I mean you you started off graphql to
overcome the rest challenges but maybe
there are some good things from rest
that you also need to put into graph
like yeah okay okay I think I think that
the the notion is here during
development cycle everyone should just
move as fast as they can and in
production depends on how you interact
with your customers or your developer
client server app whatever mobile
website then you can enforce different
rules or different strategies or
mitigations uh
approaches but and that's fairly depends
on how your org is leveraging
graphql some don't expose Graff kill
outside at all and use it as a internal
data Hub so teams can interact with yeah
in fact I based on this I had a question
because I came across an article which
said graphql is not meant to be exposed
over the Internet so what are your
thoughts on that uh it's it's it's a
it's a fair argument like if you want to
if you want to strip down what it does
it's basically SQL to the world anyone
can ask you any question and do you want
to allow it or not and we're seeing so
many different examples and companies
thinking about this the example I gave
before when Graff kill is an internal
Hub of data and you have multiple teams
that get rest request but everyone send
internally a graph request to figure out
to to reply right that's all valid I
don't think there is one way to go I
question the people that say there's
only one way to go because that's that's
that's not how create Innovation that's
not how you move fast you have to move
fast you have to make mistakes and learn
from them and learn from like examples
that exist out there tools out there we
don't in vent everything from again and
again and again to invent the wheel but
you still have to try new stuff so I'm
not saying graph graph girl should be
exposed for some companies and for some
companies it shouldn't it really depends
on your particular use case your schema
what you're trying to expose and all of
that things is no and and how mature
your engineering team is okay because
some companies are like super technical
and want to innovate and some companies
move at a different pace and they want
to try things out in more safe place
don't want to make risk we're seeing
even Legacy companies that used to use
soap are moving saying okay it's time to
replace our stack and now graph kill is
mainstream it's a it's a very good
alternative based on their use case but
you still want to move in phases maybe
not exposing graphql to the world is
part of your adoption phases as your org
is
Shifting and down the road you might be
willing to say oh we're mature enough
we're ready to expose it it really not
only depending the type of company you
are but also where are you in your
journey of GRA adoption and we meet
companies in all sort of adoption phases
of graphql the way we map it is you have
the ones who explore they're just like
oh let's find our first graph project
our first sever implementation let's
connect this to all this databases and
that's great and then you have the
second wave of it uh phase of like let's
put some safeguards for our developers
and let's start talking about schema
checks and maybe operation registry and
maybe linting and then you also have a
phase of acceleration when you really
want to like Advance monitoring think
about performance maybe think about
subgraph and think about how do we how
do we make sense of all those errors
that happen in our system and do we have
some sense of health
check from there they might or might not
move to the intelligent phase we're like
is there any bi in all this traffic can
we have alerts can we have anomaly
detection can we identify how the schema
changed over
time and and the last one you might find
your spot the the adoption Journey does
not mean you have to completed it's like
where you are at at the stage of your
company might be fine the last one is
really governance and compliance like
this is a free nature API do we know who
can access what and can we answer during
an incident actually access what this
might not be a problem for most
organizations so five steps of adoption
Journey that not everyone needs to go
through and not necessarily in this
specific order okay there are some
interesting takeaways there I do see
this whole piece on the observability
piece which you said it seems to be like
a big thing you know exactly knowing who
is using your graphql API is how it's
being used which is uh really standing
out through a lot of your the advice
you're giving the next question is I
wanted to ask about this graphql
deployments can they be secured because
I think I remember reading this article
from you which says Dev secops must turn
the tables on graphql API attackers so
can you tell us a little bit about this
I let's go back to that kubernetes
example that we started with saying like
it started with developers it brought to
devops team and then the security teams
realized two minutes later
hey what is this how do we secure it how
do we have monitor it how do we gain
control over it what is it exposing and
really a whole ecosystem of kubernetes
security came around it so we are at the
phase of GRA adoption that it does not
need to be an
afterthought you can from day one even
if you don't have a Federated
environment even if you're just
starting from day one you already now
can have the knowledge the educations
maybe the tool s from they want to set
your team for Success because the
reality is that cisos don't know much
about graphql today they're like what do
I have a graphql server they're like in
this discovery inventory
phase and when there will and when there
will be a massive incident of Graf down
the road people will wake
up so as as you are representing your
order
at what stage you want your company to
be when they're going to come for you
your own Dev SE Ops or your own security
how is your Graal security posture looks
like this is just an internal my goal
here is for encourage everyone here to
have an internal conversation internally
with their own team what is our
posture and that's it just a
conversation like this alone will take
you 8020 will take you far way down the
road than you are today so that is is
the goal of this like like pieces this
blog post that we're releasing encourage
education encourage discussions because
your or have a lot of smart people I'm
sure of it bring them to the table to
discuss this new this new technology you
we all love to introduce to okay so so
just to get back on that the the
deployment piece uh like so you're
saying that the maturity should be like
the same way like how the kubernetes
that whole ecosystem that developed is
is that what you're saying so the I mean
is it like that is it at that stage or
are you saying that we need to get
better both both both both I guess
saying this there are things everyone
can now include in their cicd deployment
model that can Harden in their
deployment right you could run a scanner
against your graphql you could write uh
QA scripts that try to access Fields
they're not supposed to you should ask
yourself is introspection open or not
you should ask yourself about rate
limiting all those rules you should be
able to identify that the change in the
schema is not breaking production
because you remove the field or because
it used to cost one millisecond and now
it's 100 millisecond and you realize
it's part of your test development so
this all needs to happen ideally happen
in a robust deployment model early
before it hits production because of all
the challenges we talked about the early
you find it like in anything else uh the
better the posture is
okay I wanted to ask the question like I
think just to kind of try to marry in a
lot of the things that you said so do
you have any top three recommendations
to prevent graphql
attacks look first one is observability
for sure you have to elevate those field
level analytics elevate subgraph ability
Elevate errors in your system do you
even know when subgraph are returning
errors about authentication someone
trying to act the field do you no this
so first remove the blind covers and get
intimate with your graphc traffic that's
the first thing I would recommend second
thing I would recommend is the really
bare bone of Cory
protections put some knobs around how
Cory should look like and what does it
do and the third will most likely be
rate
limiting going back to the the inbound
rate limiting give rules on how many
specific field can be asked in a query
and that's a good Baseline to start and
then you can have more Advance rate
limiting once you have this in mind but
just make sure like the classic Brute
Force attempts are prevented per Cory
before started having like a a redest
database that start calculating R limit
in a course these are like most advanced
things more advanced things but you have
to start somewhere so these are the
three things I would
recommend know what's going on which is
observability put some controls of how
query should look like and top level
rate limiting when it comes to field
level okay that's great so I guess the
last question I want to ask you and I
want you to spend some time is to tell
us what exactly your company does in
this space in the graphql ecosystem and
how is it helping adopters of graphql
when we when Inigo started kind of
looked at the graphql ecosystem and we
saw this like tremendous developer and
open- Source efforts to get started
build a lot of graph servers focus on
database connectivity allow people to
get started at the same time we saw
those Enterprise first graph movers
struggle to put us in production because
a lot of the topics we talked about
today we talked about security
observability maybe schema management
what does it mean to have schema checks
and linting and a graphical playground
or a good implementations of operation
registry so we wanted we wanted to
innovate at that space wanted to create
a layer that does all the management
layer that is needed for organizations
to feel confident with graphql that will
work with any implementation of graphql
so think about it so we build uh some
sort of a middleware integration that
will work with any open- source
implementations of graphql from
JavaScript to yoga to Ruby to Apollo
server it really doesn't matter and once
it's connected to it it provides all the
building blocks you might need for your
platform teams for your graphical
adoption to really continue this motion
of Journey to and then and give you that
that building blocks they needed that
will free you up even if down the road
you need to make
changes meaning moving from python to
Ruby you still have a declarative
management layer that will carry on with
you and something that is built as an
Enterprise grade solution that can
handle tens of billions of monthly calls
that have real time protection not an
afterthought that gives you the comp
position and registry that really
empowers your organization to move
forward and we love gra that's what we
do every day this is what the team is
focused on every day our tools
completely reading with graphql and we
love we love the success stories we love
to see people looking at their field
level analytics and say oh I like this
or unique Notions of air impact like we
have a lot of errors in the system
everyone has a lot of errors in their
system what's important how can we help
them prioritize it so we go deep there
yeah I think it's been uh very
interesting for me also to look at this
amount of analysis that you should do to
actually secure your graph ql API so I
think that's it's been nice because I
think you've asked cly the listeners to
dig deep with some great strategy on
observability query protection and rate
limiting I think those three things I'll
sleep with that tonight yeah this is
great the last thing I need to ask you
before I let you go is where can
listeners find you on cyberspace what is
your preferred way that people can reach
you well at Shahar at enoo you can
always go to enoo we have an active
slack Channel you can find me on
LinkedIn find me on Twitter you can
email me it's the best way very
responsive we love we love hearing
stories we love learning from others
because people went through a lot and
whatever we can generalize productize
and give
we have a very generous free tier so
wherever we can give back to those who
are starting or have a startup and
growing one piece of mine when it comes
to graphql we love those success stories
great I'll make sure to add that on our
show notes at least your LinkedIn
profile as well as your the Indigo site
which I already have this has been great
thanks for coming on the show Shahar it
was a pleasure pranka thank you for
having me really enjoy the
conversation this is Priyanka Ragin for
software engineering radio thanks for
listening thanks for listening to SC
radio an educational program brought to
you by It software magazine for more
about the podcast including other
episodes visit our website at
sr. to provide feedback you can comment
on each episode on the website or reach
us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter or
through our slack Channel at seo.
slack.com you can also email us at team
e-
radio.net this and all other episodes of
SC radio is licensed under Creative
Commons license
2.5 thanks for listening